Office of the Vice President for Business and Finance records, 1950-ongoing UA.10.01.0003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of the Vice President for Business and Finance records
1950-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of the Vice President for Business and Finance
UA.10.01.0003
93.5 Linear Feet
Contains memoranda, correspondence, budgets, reports, agreements, financial information, organizational records and other printed matter from the Office of the Vice President for Business and Finance. Records concern Duke University, its various academic departments, organizations, and benefactors, including the Medical Center. These records were created by Vice President for Business and Finance Gerhard Henricksen (1962-1966) and his successor Charles B. Huestis (1966-1985), and provide a detailed account of the university's financial status. Major topics include the university's relationship with the Duke Endowment and Local Unions 77 and 465, Medical Center construction;, university properties, physical plant, and facilities renovations, national professional organizations, several university committees, the Board of Trustees, the Duke University Athletic Association, WDBS campus radio station, the Duke Vigil, Duke University Marine Lab, Huestis' personal interests and affiliations, and the departments of the Business and Finance Division (including Housing, Data Processing and the Computation Center, Accounting, Dining Halls, Personnel, Materials Support, Safety and Traffic, TelCom, and Utilities), and the University Architect. Major correspondents include University Architect, University Council, Business Manager, Corporate and University Controllers, Terry Sanford, William G. Anlyan, A. Kenneth Pye, Richard L. Jackson, J. Peyton Fuller, John Adcock. English.
Access Restrictions
Access restricted. For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
Provenance
Gift; 1976; A76-40 (Box 1); Unknown provenance; 1976; A76-151 (Box 2); Transfer; 1976; A76-151 (Boxes 3-13); Transfer; 1977; 77-46 (Boxes 1-7 and 8-11); Transfer; 1978; A78-129 (Boxes 14-31); Transfer; 1981; A81-81; (Boxes 32-36); Transfer; 1983; A83-57 (Box 37); Transfer; 1986; A85-116 (Boxes 38-44); Transfer; 1985; A86-51 (Boxes 45-47); Transfer; 1998; A98-32 (Boxes 48-51); Transfer; 2011; UA2011-0006 (Boxes 52-56); Transfer; 2012; UA2012-0003 (Boxes 57-58); Transfer, 2014; UA2014.0083 (Boxes 59-74); Gift; 2017; UA2017-0081 (Box 59)
Historical Note
The Vice President for Business and Finance was the chief fiscal officer of the university, and reported to the President. The position was established in 1962, and was superseded in 1985 by the position of Executive (or Senior) Vice President. The officer was responsible for fiscal planning, preparation of the budget, and supervision of the University's non-academic programs. Ordinarily, the Vice President for Business and Finance was responsible for signing formal requests for grants and contracts submitted to government agencies and foundations, and had custody of contracts, deeds agreements, and other documents relating to the University's non-academic operations.
The Vice President for Business and Finance was responsible for Duke's entire Business and Finance Division; at various times in division history the positions of Business Manager, Treasurer, Controller, University Architect, and Vice President for Administration and Health Affairs reported to the Vice President for Business and Finance. The Vice President for Business and Finance was also responsible for such departments as Physical Plant, Personnel, Business Auxiliaries (including Dining Halls, Stores, and Housing divisions), Material Support, Internal Audit, Data Processing, Public Safety, and Accounting, among others.
Occupants of the position were Gerhard C. Henricksen, 1962-1966, and Charles B. Huestis, 1966-1985.
Gerhard Henricksen (1907-1994) came to Duke in 1936 as an internal auditor. He was promoted to Assistant Comptroller and Assistant Business Manager in 1948, Comptroller and Assistant Treasurer in 1956, Comptroller and Business Manager in 1958, and Assistant to the President for Business and Finance in 1961. In 1962, Henricksen was appointed to fill the newly created position of Vice President for Business and Finance, a position he held until his promotion to Vice President and Treasurer of the university in 1966.
Henricksen was succeeded as Vice President of Business and Finance by Charles B. Huestis (1920-), who came to Duke from Hughes Aircraft Company in 1966. Huestis served as the Vice President for Business and Finance for the next 19 years, retiring in 1985. In addition to his professional duties at Duke, Huestis also served as a director of the Durham Investment Company and Research Triangle Foundation, was an active Sierra Club member and mountain climbing enthusiast (including participating in the 1963 American Mt. Everest Expedition), served on numerous university committees, and was a member of "The Troika" which guided the university during the period between presidents in 1969. Huestis was succeeded as Senior Vice President by Eugene McDonald.
Collection Overview
Contains memoranda, correspondence, budgets, reports, agreements, financial information, organizational records and other printed matter pertaining to the financial status Duke University's academic departments, organizations, benefactors, and Medical Center. Major topics include Duke University's relationship with the Duke Endowment and Local Unions 77 and 465, the Internal Audit Office, the Chancellor's Office, the Board of Trustees, Medical Center construction, university properties, parking, the physical plant, facilities renovations, the Environmental Concerns Committee, Research Triangle Park, Research Triangle Institute, highway development, the Duke University Athletic Association, WDBS campus radio station, Duke University Marine Lab, Duke Forest, Charles B. Huestis, C. G. Henricksen, the American Dance Festival, business auxiliaries, departments of the Business and Finance Division (including Housing, Data Processing and the Computation Center, Accounting, Dining Halls, Personnel, Materials Support, Safety and Traffic, Utilities, and the TelCom division), the Duke Vigil, and the University Architect. Major correspondents include University Architect, University Council, Business Manager, Corporate and University Controllers, Terry Sanford, William G. Anlyan, and A. Kenneth Pye. Subject files are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
Business Division Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Business and Finance Division records. Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Campus parking -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke Forest (N.C.); Highway planning -- North Carolina -- Durham County; Labor unions -- United States; Land use; Research Triangle Park (N.C.) -- History; Telephone systems; Anlyan, William G.; Duke Endowment -- History; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Buildings -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- Finance; Duke University -- Student housing; Duke University -- Students -- Political activity; Ward, James A., 1915-; WDBS (Radio station: Durham, N.C.); Research Triangle Institute -- History; Sanford, Terry; Adcock, John F.; American Dance Festival; AFSCME. Local 77; Duke University. University Counsel; Duke University. University Architect; Henricksen, Gerhard Chester, 1907-1994; Duke University. University Planning Committee; International Union of Operating Engineers. Local 465; Huestis, Charles B., 1920-; Research Triangle Foundation -- History; Pye, A. Kenneth; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Athletic Dept; Duke University. Medical Center -- Buildings; Duke University. Marine Laboratory -- History; Duke University. Medical Center -- History; Duke University. Medical Center -- Design and construction; Duke University. Office of the President
- Accession 76-40.
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains the professional and personal subject files of Gerhard Henricksen from 1962-1966, the period during which he served as Vice-President for Business and Finance.
  Arrangement note
  Ordered alphabetically.
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Durham Industrial Education Center, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Eastward (Duke Marine Lab boat), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Economic Opportunity Program, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Engineering, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Geology Dept., 1964 (Box 1)
  - Gift Acknowledgment Receipts, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Gift Reception Center, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Indirect Cost Rate, FY 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Institutional Advancement, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - J. A. Jones Construction Co., 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Kiwanis, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Knight, Douglas - Comparative Statements, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Loyalty Fund, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Mathematics Dept., 1964 (Box 1)
  - Naming of Duke Roads and Entrances Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - National Association of College and University Business Officers (NACUBO) Newsletter, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - National Fund for Medical Education, 1964 (Box 1)
  - NIH Grants, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Organizational Chart, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Physics Dept., 1965 (Box 1)
  - Scholarships and Loans, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Private Financing, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Public Health Service - Grant Regulations, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Purchasing Dept., 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Research Triangle of NC (includes maps, proposals), 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Salary Reduction Plans, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Southern Association of College and University Business Officers (SACUBO), 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Scholarships and Loans, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Social Security System, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Student Housing, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Taxes, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Teachers Insurance & Annuity Association of American/College Retirement Equities Fund (TIAA/CREF) Telephone Exchange, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Telephone Exchange, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - United States Office of Education, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Wachovia Bank, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
- Accession 76-151.
  Contains miscellaneous records created by the office of the Vice-President for Business and Finance and its predecessor, the Business Division, primarily in the form of clippings, reports, and handbooks. One item of note is a handbook titled "President's Book," which appears to have been a reference manual created to introduce new president Douglas Knight to the university's basic financial status. Materials range in date from 1963-1979.
  Ordered chronologically.
  - Clippings, 1973-1979 (Box 2)
  - "The Organization of Business and Finance," 1964 (Box 2)
  - "Presidents Book," 1963 (Box 2)
  - Report on Investments, FY 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Accession 77-46.
  This series contains budgetary, Duke Endowment, and Research Triangle Institute information, as well as materials regarding the University Planning Committee, traffic and parking concerns, local union activity, and the 1968 vigil. Also contains a large amount of correspondence between Huestis and the Personnel Department, Medical Center administrators, and other university officials.
  - Academic Council, 1966-1973 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Officers, Memos to, 1967-1972 (Box 3)
  - Aircraft, 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - Affirmative Action, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1967-1972 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education, 1968-1973 (Box 3)
  - American Management Association, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - American Oil Foundation, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Association of Eastern North Carolina Colleges, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Athletics Association, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Banks Anderson Fund, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees--Reports, Agendas, Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Board of Trustees materials are RESTRICTED.
  - Booz-Allen & Hamilton (financial consultants), 1968-1972 (Box 3)
  - Booz-Allen & Hamilton Inter-institutional Salary Survey, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Bryson, E. C. (University Council), 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Budget and Audit Committee (Box 4)
    Budget and Audit Committee materials are RESTRICTED.
  - Budget Request, School of Nursing 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Budget Request, Medical Center, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Budget Request, School of Medicine, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Budget Request, University Health Services, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Budgets, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Budgets Forecasts, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Budget (Proposed), Medical Center Administration, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Budget (Proposed), School of Medicine, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Budget Request, University Health Services, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Burlington Industries Foundation grant (Box 4)
  - Business and Finance Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Business Manager (Jim Adams), [2 folders] (Box 4)
  - CC Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Chemistry Building (Box 4)
  - Construction (Box 4)
  - Civil Rights (Box 4)
  - Commencement (Box 4)
  - Computation Center and Data Processing (Box 4)
  - Computer Science (Box 4)
  - Data Processing (Box 5)
  - Dining Halls (Box 5)
  - Duke/Durham Community (Box 5)
  - Duke Endowment (x3) -- also includes bound booklets: annual Duke Endowment Requests, 1967-1969, and annual Proposals from Duke to the Endowment, 1971-1972, [3 folders] (Box 5)
  - Duke Homestead (Box 5)
  - Duke/UNC Comparisons (regarding fringe benefits) (Box 5)
  - Duke University Marine Lab (Box 5)
  - Faculty Committee on Student Concerns (Box 5)
  - FM Educational Broadcasting Station (Box 5)
  - Green, John (Special Projects) correspondence (Box 5)
  - Hobbs, Marcus (Provost) correspondence (Box 5)
  - Hospital Renovation (Box 5)
  - Housing Bureau (Box 5)
  - Housing, East Campus (Box 6)
  - Kerr Lake (Box 6)
  - Knight, Doug (Box 6)
  - Library Construction (Box 6)
  - Maintenance (W. K. Howard) (Box 6)
  - Maintenance - Plant (Box 6)
  - Management Services Dept. (J. L. Adams) (Box 6)
  - Material Support Dept. (J. L. Adams) (Box 6)
  - Medical Center -- General (W. G. Anlyan, VP for Health Affairs) (Box 6)
  - Medical Center -- (L. E. Swanson, Dir. of Planning) (Box 6)
  - Overtime (Box 6)
  - Parking (Box 6)
  - Paths for Employees' Progress (PEP) Program (Box 6)
  - Personnel (W. R. Linke, Dir.), 1966-1969 (Box 7)
  - Personnel (W. R. Linke, Dir.), 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Personnel Policy Committee (Box 7)
  - Physical Plant (Harry Ebert, Dir.) (Box 7)
  - Phytotron (Box 7)
  - Project Outreach (Box 7)
  - Proudfoot Company Reports (Work Scheduling, Duke Libraries, etc.) (Box 7)
  - Publicity (Box 7)
  - Rauch, Henry E. -- Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Regulations (on alcohol possession/consumption on campus and dorm visitation by opposite sex) Survey of other schools 1967 (Box 7)
  - Rehabilitation Facility, Phase I (Box 7)
  - Rehabilitation Facility, Phase II (Box 7)
  - Research Triangle Foundation (Box 7)
  - Research Triangle Organization (Box 8)
  - Research Triangle Institute, [4 folders] (Box 8)
  - ROTC (Box 8)
  - Safety Security Div., [2 folders] (Box 8)
  - Special Trustee-Administrative Committee (on pickets, protests, and employee relations) (Box 8)
  - Strike (employee), 1968 (Box 8)
  - Telephone System (Box 8)
  - T. Rowe Price Assoc. (investment consultants) (Box 8)
  - T. Rowe Price Assoc., [2 folders] (Box 9)
  - University Planning Committee, [2 folders] (Box 9)
  - University Policy and Planning Committee (UPPAC) (Box 9)
  - Union Activity (Box 9)
  - Vigil (Box 9)
  - Wage and Salary (Box 9)
  - Work Scheduling Program (Box 9)
  - Administrative Council, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Air Pollution, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Architects, 1966-1975 (Box 10)
  - Asbury Demolition, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Ashmore, Frank (VP Institutional Advancement) -- Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 10)
  - Betterments Projects, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
  - Blacknall Residence, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Blue Book, 1968-1973 (Box 10)
  - Brummer Art Collection, 1968-1973 (Box 10)
  - Budget-General, 1969-1974 (Box 10)
  - Budget Forecasts, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Blackburn, John (Chancellor) -- Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
  - Chapel, 1969-1974 (Box 10)
  - Chronicle, 1968-1974 (Box 10)
  - Commencement, 1967-1972 (Box 10)
  - Cost Improvement, 1967-1972 (Box 10)
  - Demonstrations -- Vigil, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Detomo, Paul (Business Manager) -- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - DeVyver, Frank (Economics Dept.) -- Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box 10)
  - Dining Halls, 1972-1975 (Box 10)
  - Duke Endowment, 1971-1973 (Box 10)
  - Duke University Employee Relations Advisory Committee (DUERAC), 1968-1972 (Box 10)
  - Duke Himalaya Expedition, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Duke Marine Lab Expansion, 1971-1975 (Box 10)
  - Durham Hotel (Possible Acquisition), 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Eastward, 1963-1973 (Box 10)
  - Educational Administration Advisory Group, 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - Electrical Utility Study, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Employee Health Services (non-academic), 1970-1974 (Box 10)
  - Employee's Council, 1968-1970 (Box 10)
  - Employment Practices Associates, 1972-1974 (Box 10)
  - Employee Relations (Herbert Aikens, Dir.), 1968-1973 (Box 10)
  - Enrollment, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - Executive Jet Association, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Club, 1967-1975 (Box 10)
  - Fiber Industries (factory proposal near Duke Forest), 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Fifth Decade Campaign, 1967-1972 (Box 11)
  - Financial Reports, 1967-1973 (Box 11)
  - Financial Aid, 1969-1973 (Box 11)
  - First Union national bank, 1971-1973 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation, 1966-1972 (Box 11)
  - Fringe Benefits (Faculty), 1969 (Box 11)
  - Gifts -- Unrestricted/Unallocated, 1967-1968 (Box 11)
  - Gifts -- Unrestricted/Unallocated, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Gifts and Grants, 1966-1973 (Box 11)
  - Governmental Affairs, 1967-1970 (Box 11)
  - Governance (University), 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - Grant Purchased Equipment, 1967-1970 (Box 11)
  - Graphic Arts Building, 1969-1972 (Box 11)
  - Haw River Property, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Henricksen, C. G. (Consulting), 1967-1974 (Box 11)
  - Higher Education Facilities Commission, 1967-1969 (Box 11)
  - Highland Hospital, 1964-1967 (Box 11)
  - Highland Hospital, 1967-1974 (Box 11)
  - Highway 751, 1969-1974 (Box 11)
  - Home sites (Duke Faculty), 1967-1973 (Box 11)
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD), 1967-1975 (Box 11)
  - Housing (Student), 1969-1973 (Box 11)
  - Housing -- Married Students, 1967-1970 (Box 11)
  - Housing -- Off-Campus, 1967-1972 (Box 11)
  - Hyperbaric Chamber, 1967-1970 (Box 11)
  - Learning Institute of N.C. (LINK), 1968-1972 (Box 11)
  - Maintenance and Operations, 1966-1975 (Box 11)
  - Major Speakers, 1967-1973 (Box 11)
  - Marshall Collection, 1966-1973 (Box 11)
  - Material Support, 1967-1973 (Box 11)
  - Medi-Data, 1972-1974 (Box 11)
  - National Institutes of Health (NIH) Grants, 1967-1972 (Box 12)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1968-1974 (Box 12)
  - N.C. Medical Care Comm. -- Duke-Civitan Developmental Evaluation Clinic, 1966-1972 (Box 12)
  - Operation Breakthrough (Neighborhood Youth Corps), 1968-1973 (Box 12)
  - Organs (Duke Chapel), 1966-1974 (Box 12)
  - Payroll, 1967-1975 (Box 12)
  - Payroll Policy Petition, Nov. 6, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Personnel, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Personnel Grievances, 1967-1970 (Box 12)
  - Personnel, Med. Center, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
  - Physical Plant (F. Bowers, Dir.), Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 12)
  - Policies and Procedures, 1967-1970 (Box 12)
  - Policies and Procedures, 1971-1973 (Box 12)
  - Property/Real Estate, 1969-1973 (Box 12)
  - Property/Real Estate -- Marine Lab (Wallace House), 1972 (Box 12)
  - Property/Real Estate -- Southland Associates, 1970-1974 (Box 12)
  - Public Safety (Dumas, Dir.), 1971-1974 (Box 12)
  - Raleigh-Durham Aviation, 1968-1975 (Box 12)
  - Retirement, 1966-1973 (Box 12)
  - Sea Level Hospital, 1969-1974 (Box 12)
  - Secretary of the University (R. H. Powell] -- Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 12)
  - Student Activities, 1967-1972 (Box 12)
  - Student Health, 1967-1972 (Box 12)
  - Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Assoc. (TIAA), 1967-1973 (Box 12)
  - Teer House, 1967-1971 (Box 12)
  - Telephone System, 1966-1970 (Box 12)
  - Telephone System and Building, 1971-1978 (Box 12)
  - Traffic Commission, 1967-1971 (Box 12)
  - Traffic Commission, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Traffic -- Parking, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - Traffic -- Parking, 1972-1975 (Box 12)
  - Triangle Universities Computation Center (TUCC), 1966-1973 (Box 13)
  - Trustees -- Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 13)
  - Trustees-Executive Committee -- Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 13)
    Trustees materials are RESTRICTED.
  - Tuition, 1967-1974 (Box 13)
  - Union Activity, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Union Activity, 1971-1973 (Box 13)
  - Union Activity -- Local 77, 1967-1971 (Box 13)
  - United Durham, Inc. (UDI), 1971-1975 (Box 13)
  - University Stores, 1967-1973 (Box 13)
  - Wachovia Bank, 1966-1976 (Box 13)
  - Wade, Charles (Chairman of the Board) -- Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box 13)
  - WDBS, 1969-1973 (Box 13)
- Accession 78-129.
  This series is dominated by records of Business and Finance Division departments, especially Business Auxiliaries, Housing Management, Personnel, Physical Plant, and Special Utilities. The latter department underwent significant growth and change during this time, including the construction of a 44KV electrical substation and TelCom division, and expansion of the telephone and electrical power capabilities of the university. This series also includes materials from the many university committees on which Huestis served or which reported to him, including the Building and Grounds, Environmental Concerns, Investment, Personnel Policy, and Residential Life committees. Also contains considerable financial information concerning budgetary matters, the Duke Endowment, and Duke University Athletic Association. This series may be the best source of information on the history of WDBS, and is also thorough in its representation of local trade unions and the Research Triangle Park. Two boxes are devoted to Medical Center records, which are dominated by financial information, correspondence to Medical Center administrators, and reports on the construction of Duke Hospital North. T. Rowe Price folders contain comprehensive monthly reports on university investments and other aspects of the university's financial status. Boxes 28-31 contain official handouts and agendas from meetings of the Board of Trustees and its subordinate body, the Executive Committee, whose meetings coincided with those of the larger Board. Materials range in date from 1966-1975.
  - Academic Council, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - ACT Erwin Council, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Administrative Committee on Development, 1970-1971 (Box 14)
  - Admissions and Financial Aid, 1967-1974 (Box 14)
  - Affirmative Action, 1970-1972 (Box 14)
  - Affirmative Action, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1966-1976 (Box 14)
  - Anatomy Dept., 1967-1974 (Box 14)
  - Annual Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - Architect, University, J. Ward, 1969-1974 (Box 14)
  - Architect, University, J. Ward, 1975 (Box 14)